Finding Aid for University Architect's Office (University of Michigan) Records, ca. 1950-1989.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- University Buildings Files
  - Dearborn Campus
    - Dearborn Center
      - Reports
        - "Investigation and Recommendations Relative to Access Roads and Utilities" (Giffels and Vallet, Inc., and L. Rossetti) 1957 (Box 18)
    - Engineering Laboratory Building--Remodeling
      - General
        - Correspondence 1971-1976 (Box 19)
    - General Classroom and Laboratory Building
      - General Correspondence 1974-1977 (Box 19)
      - Meeting Notes 1975-1977 (Box 19)
      - Reports
        - "Program Space Analysis" (Tarapata MacMahon Paulsen Corp.) December 9, 1975 (Box 19)
        - "Schematic Design Documents" (Tarapata MacMahon Paulsen Associates, Inc.) September 1, 1976 (Box 19)
    - Library
      - Addition
        - Bids and Proposals 1970 (Box 19)
        - Conference Notes 1969-1970 (Box 19)
        - Contract 1969 (Box 19)
        - General Correspondence 1969-1972 (Box 19)
        - Reports
          - "Project Document Submission" (Charles W. Sherman Associates, Inc.) July 1, 1974 (Box 19)
    - Library and Learning Resources Center
      - Bid and Proposals 1974-1978 (Box 19)
      - Contract 1975 (Box 19)
      - Correspondence
        - Architect 1971-1978 (Box 19)
        - General 1972-1979 (Box 19)
      - Meeting Notes 1973-1974 (Box 19)
      - Program Statement 1973 (Box 19)
      - Reports
        - "Project Analysis" (Office of Capital Planning) June 8, 1973 (Box 19)
        - "Prospectus Statement" (Office of Capital Planning) August 20, 1971 (Box 19)
    - Recreation Building
      - Correspondence 1976-1979 (Box 19)
    - Student Activities Building
      - Addition (Project #353) (Box 19)
      - Contracts 1973-1974 (Box 19)
      - General Correspondence 1973-1974 (Box 19)
      - Report and Supporting Documents
        - "Facilities Program," April 25, 1973 Report-"Alterations to: Student Activity Building and Engineering Building" (Louis G. Redstone Associates, Inc.), April 15, 1970 (Box 19)
    - Surge Building 1971-1976 (Box 19)
    - University Mall and Field House
      - Correspondence 1978-1980 (Box 19)
  - Flint Campus
    - Campus Relocation
      - General Correspondence 1970-1972 (Box 19)
      - Reports
        - "Assembling a Riverfront Site for the University of Michigan-Flint: Volume 11-Exhibits, Maps and Appendix A," September 15, 1972 (Box 19)
        - "Centric 80.. ." June 25, 1971 (Box 19)
        - "Site Investigation: Riverfront Site Proposal" (Sasaki, Dawson, DeMay Associates, Inc.) September 19, 1972 (Box 19)
        - "Subsoil Investigation and Foundation Feasibility Study" (Raymond C. Reese Associates) 1972 (Box 19)
    - Classroom and Office Building
      - General 1970-1977 (Box 19)
      - Reports
        - "Construction Management Proposal: University of Michigan-Flint Classroom Building" (Samborn, Steketee, Otis and Evans, Inc.) 1972 (Box 19)
        - "Project Analysis: Classroom and Office Building, University of Michigan-Flint" 1971, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Classroom/Laboratory Building
      - Contract 1986 (Box 20)
      - Correspondence
        - Architect 1984-1987 (Box 20)
        - University of Michigan 1983-1987 (Box 20)
        - General 1984-1986 (Box 20)
      - Prospectus 1974 (Box 20)
      - Reports
        - "Development Phase" (Smith, Hinchman and Grylls Associates) December 1, 1984 (Box 20)
        - "Schematic Design" (Smith, Hinchman and Grylls Associates) July 5, 1984 (Box 20)
    - Library
      - Library/Learning Resource Center
        - Correspondence
          - Architect 1985-1988 (Box 20)
          - University of Michigan 1985-1988 (Box 20)
          - General 1985-1991 (Box 20)
        - Meeting Minutes 1985-1987 (Box 20)
        - Photograph of Model undated (Box 20)
        - Reports
          - "Facility Program: Library/Telecommunications Center" (Gunnar Birkerts and Associates) April 1986 (Box 20)
          - "Feasibility Analysis: Library Building" (Gunnar Birkerts and Associates) June 1, 1987 (Box 20)
          - "Schematic Design Submittal (Preliminary): Library/Telecommunications Center" (Gunnar Birkerts and Associates) September 3, 1986 (Box 20)
      - Frances Willson Thompson Library
        - Budgets 1992 (Box 20)
        - Contract 1992 (Box 20)
        - Correspondence
          - University of Michigan 1991-1992 (Box 20)
          - General 1992 (Box 20)
        - Meeting Notes and Architect Correspondence 1990-1993, 4 folders (Box 20)
    - Parking Structure 1986 (Box 20)
    - Ross House (Project #337)-General Correspondence 1971-1972 (Box 20)
    - Surge Building A-General Correspondence 1972-1974 (Box 20)
    - University Center-General Correspondence 1973, 1978 (Box 20)
  - Other Locations
    Other Locations consists of information on remote facilities and field stations including the Peach Mountain observatory, Biological Station, and the Botanical Gardens.
    - Astronomy Building, Peach Mountain 1962-1969 (Box 20)
    - Biological Station
      - Biological Station 1976, 1981-1987 (Box 20)
      - Waterfront Laboratory Building, Biological Station, Report, "Planning, Site and Building" (The Architects Collective) undated (Box 20)
    - Botanical Gardens
      - Report
        - "The University of Michigan Botanical Gardens Building and Site Development" (Alden B. Dow Associates) undated (Box 20)
Related Material
For further information regarding building projects at the University of Michigan, researchers may wish to consult the following record groups which contain similar documentation: University of Michigan. University Planner's Office; University of Michigan. Building and Grounds Department; University of Michigan. Plant Extension Services; University of Michigan Architectural Drawings; as well as the papers of the Pond Family. Additional building and construction information is also typically available in central administrative record groups (i.e., President, Provost and Executive Vice President for Academic Affairs), individual schools and colleges, and units such as the Institute for Social Research and Library.